(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
重大告知アリ!!
Major Announcement!!
ホロメン＆サクラ大戦から豪華ゲスト!?
Gorgeous guests from Holomen & Sakura Wars!?
さらに3D新衣装!! お披露目!!
Plus, 3D New Outfit!! Reveal!!
本日の議題
Today's Agenda
ライブ1曲目の衣装は何が良い??
What outfit is good for the first song of the live??
ケンカしない
Don't fight
一味にもっといいところ見せたいよ〜〜
I want to show the Ichimi an even better side of me~~
Dancing Marine!
もっと Marine!
More Marine!
愛シテル!
I love you!
ムクロビッツ　シゴノビッツ
Mukurobitzu Shigonobitzu
ムクロビッツ
Mukurobitzu
シゴノビッツ
Shigonobitzu
ムクロビッツ
Mukurobitzu
シゴノビッツ
Shigonobitzu
ムクロデッビ
Mukuro de Be
死んじゃって御愁傷　アミヨデッビ
My condolences on your death, Amida de Be
でも存外楽しい　地獄でPeace Peace Peace
But it's surprisingly fun, Peace Peace Peace in Hell
もうクヨクヨしないで
Don't worry about it anymore
ほら高い高い愛シテル
Look, I love you so much
切り替えてこうぜ　Dance Dance Chu
Let's switch it up, Dance Dance Chu
むくらDancing Dancing Chu Chu Chu
Mukura Dancing Dancing Chu Chu Chu
キスでChu Chu Chu
A kiss with a Chu Chu Chu
でもベッドはChu Chu Chu
But in bed it's Chu Chu Chu
Dance Dance Chu
むくらDancing Dancing Chu Chu Chu
Mukura Dancing Dancing Chu Chu Chu
ビートに夢Chu
Obsessed with the beat
甘酸っぱいChu Chu Chu
Bittersweet Chu Chu Chu
踊れ踊れし　君たちと
Dance, dance, with all of you
踊る踊る　無限にHappy Happy
Dancing, dancing, infinitely Happy Happy
Everybody　揃っていいじゃない
Everybody, isn't it fine for us to be together?
愛死体　死ねたらもう愛されたいので
I want to love you, if I die, I want to be loved
いけないの？いけないの？
Is it wrong? Is it wrong?
ありがたき幸せならば　チュしてね
If it's a blessing, please give me a kiss
契約　分かったら返事
If you understand the contract, give me an answer
感服しました負けました　地獄最高！
I'm impressed, I've lost, Hell is the best!
あちら正面　寂しいですか？
Over there in front, are you lonely?
マリンがいるでしょう
Marine is here, right?
誰かがフライング　愛愛Aye
Someone is jumping the gun, Love Love Aye
待って　どうせ今生なんて
Wait, since this life is what it is
待って　港のひとつ
Wait, just one of the ports
ねぇ待って　通り過ぎてくだけなのね
Hey wait, you're just passing through, aren't you?
待ってて言ったでしょう
I told you to wait, didn't I?
至ってノリノリ 優雅にこうしてヘラったマリンの
I'm in high spirits, elegantly acting out like this, Marine's...
根拠なく無敵なタイガースパボディー
...groundlessly invincible Tiger Super Body
ごっそり数センチなんて正気なChu Chu Chu
A whole few centimeters, what a sane Chu Chu Chu
嵐か神みたいに窓を叩くから
Because you're knocking on the window like a storm or a god
変わる愛の流転
The changing flux of love
断然ホットなのChu Chu
It's definitely hot, Chu Chu
ハートビートは　夢中でChu
My heartbeat is obsessed, Chu
So what! かなり昭和
So what! It's so Showa.
10しゃべれば要素は
If I speak ten words, the elements are...
ビューティフル ビューティフル デイズ
beautiful, beautiful days.
美しく 笑おう 笑おう
Let's laugh beautifully, let's laugh.
エイティハグして ギュッてして
Give me an 80 hug, squeeze me tight.
ポポンッて パレードだ
Pop, pop, it's a parade.
みんなスリスリすり抜けて
Everyone, rubbing and slipping through...
何もかも手に入れたい
I want to get my hands on everything.
ギラギラギラ 暴走だ
Glistening and glaring, it's a rampage.
ごめん 美人は死んでも治りませーん
Sorry, beauties won't be cured even if they die!
ラララララ～
La la la la la~
ゲラゲラゲラ 逃亡だ
Cackling and fleeing...
地獄を謳歌だ
...enjoying hell to the fullest.
ゲラゲラゲラ 逃亡だ
Cackling and fleeing...
ゲラゲラゲラ～
Cackling~
レッツタッタリーホー 月夜と踊れや踊れ
Let's Tattari-ho, dance with the moonlit night.
レッツタッタリーホー 帆を立て歌えば風が吹く
Let's Tattari-ho, set sail and sing to catch the wind.
レッツタッタリーホー みんなまだまだ上がれ
Let's Tattari-ho, everyone, keep on rising.
レッツタッタリーホー 泡立つ波間をかき分けて
Let's Tattari-ho, pushing through the foaming waves.
イッツショウタイム！
It's showtime!
アイ！アイ！マ！ 根も葉も端っチュチュチュ
Aye! Aye! Ma! No rhyme or reason, kiss, kiss, kiss.
遊び散らかして レッツタッタリーホー
Playing all around, let's Tattari-ho.
アイ！アイ！マ！ さあ行け、そこだ
Aye! Aye! Ma! Now go, right there.
あんだわなんだわ 宵旅路を
Whatever it is, on this evening journey.
ラララララ～
La la la la la~
踊りましましたらば 無垢呂に花束を
If we have finished dancing, a bouquet for the corpse.
アゾラアゾラシーン
Azora Azora scene.
君たちとアゾラアゾラ
With you all, Azora Azora.
無敵にハッピーハッピー エブリバディ それでもいいじゃなーい
Invincible, happy, happy, everybody! Isn't that okay?
みんな大好き！
I love you all!
好き好き好き好きを 超愛してる
I love you, love you, love you, love you so much!
情けないの？ 避けないの？
Is it pathetic? Won't you avoid it?
ありがとうってしてたらば 許して許して
If I say thank you, forgive me, forgive me.
バラバラ遺骨になっても
Even if I become scattered remains...
終わらない宴を
...the banquet will never end.
ラララララ～ 楽しすぎて成仏しちゃいそう
La la la la la~ It's so fun, I might pass on.
礼拝しちゃう
I'm going to worship.
ラララララ～ 君たち
La la la la la~ You all...
センチョウのこと 呼び止めて
...call out to the Captain and stop her.
制約 成立
The contract is established.
わかったら返事、ね？
If you understand, give me an answer, okay?
はい、というわけで、マリン船長お誕生日おめでとう！
All right, and so, Captain Marine, happy birthday!
自分で祝う！
Congratulating myself!
はい、というわけで、えーとですね、早速始まりましたが
Yes, so, um, we've gotten right into it, but...
ええ、今やりました「スキスキDieスキ超Aisiteru」
...yes, that was "Suki Suki Die Suki Chou Aishiteru."
これね、そのーアルバムで入ってた曲なんですけど
That was a song from my album, but...
今日、MVが出ます！
...the MV is coming out today!
この後出るので、絶対見てください！
It'll be out after this, so please make sure to watch!
そしてね、ハッシュタグご紹介します。こちら！
And now, let me introduce the hashtag. Here it is!
えー「#宝鐘マリン生誕祭2025」でたくさん呟いてください
Please tweet a lot with "#宝鐘マリン生誕祭2025."
なんと言ってもね、今日はねもうもちろん、えーホロメンやホロライブでもない
More than anything, today, of course, besides Holomems...
あのーほぼホロメンみたいな人とか、あのーゲストに5つ
...there are people who are almost like Holomems, five guests!
そしてものすごいもう船長超念願、念願、念願、長年の念願の
And a really, really long-awaited, long-awaited dream...
えー、スペシャルゲストもね、サクラ大戦から来てくださいまーす！
...um, we also have special guests coming from Sakura Wars!
はい、そしてね、えーと、ソロライブの衣装に新しい髪型が追加されます！
Also, um, a new hairstyle will be added to my solo live outfit!
そしてさらに！新衣装も、サムネイルにちらっと映ってますけど、新衣装もあります！
And what's more! There's also a new costume, as seen in the thumbnail!
そして、一体何があるのか全く想像もつかない、重大発表が、あります！
And there will be a major announcement that you won't believe!
楽しみですね！もうこりゃあもういっぱいウキウキなトピックたくさんなので
How exciting! Since there are so many thrilling topics...
こちらのハッシュタグでね、あのー、「なんとびっくり」「うおー」つって、呟き散らかしてください！
...please tweet away with the hashtag, saying "No way!" or "Whoa!"
となわけで、ライブいっぱい楽しんでください！
So anyway, please enjoy the live show to the fullest!
うーい！
Woo-hoo!
うーい、とは。
"Woo-hoo," really?
ゲストパート、どうぞ！
Here comes the guest part!
少女レイ
Shoujo Rei
本能が狂い始める
My instincts are starting to go crazy.
追い詰められた二十日鼠
A house mouse driven into a corner.
今、絶望の淵に立って
Now, standing on the edge of despair...
踏切へと
...at the railroad crossing.
飛び出した
Jumped out
そう 君は友達 僕の手を掴めよ
That's right, you're a friend, grab my hand
そう 君は独りさ 居場所なんてないだろ
That's right, you're alone, there's no place for you, is there?
二人きりこのまま 愛し合えるさ
Just the two of us, we can love each other like this
繰り返す フラッシュバック 蝉の声 二度と帰らぬ君
Repeating flashback, cicada voices, you who will never return
永遠に千切れてく お揃いのキーホルダー
Forever tearing apart, our matching keychains
夏が消し去った 白い肌の少女に
To the girl with white skin that summer erased
哀しいほど 取り憑かれてしまいたい
I want to be possessed by you to a sad extent
反射が暴れ始める 九月のスタート告げるチャイム
Reflections begin to run wild, the chime announcing the start of September
次の標的に置かれた風 仕掛けたのは僕だった
The wind placed on the next target, I was the one who set it up
そう 君が悪いんだよ 僕だけを見ててよ
That's right, it's your fault, look only at me
そう 君の苦しみ 助けが欲しいだろ
That's right, your suffering, you want help, don't you?
溺れてくその手に そっとキスをした
I gently kissed that drowning hand
薄笑いの獣たち その心晴れるまで
The faintly smiling beasts, until that heart clears
爪を突き立てる 不揃いのスカート
Digging in claws, the uneven skirts
夏の静寂を切り裂くような悲鳴が
A scream like it's tearing through the summer silence
木霊する 教室の窓には青空
Echoing, there's a blue sky in the classroom window
君は友達
You are a friend
そう 君は友達 僕の手を掴めよ
That's right, you're a friend, grab my hand
そう 君がいなくちゃ 居場所なんてないんだよ
That's right, without you, there's no place for me
透き通った世界で 愛し合えたら
If we could love each other in a transparent world
繰り返す フラッシュバック 蝉の声 二度と帰らぬ君
Repeating flashback, cicada voices, you who will never return
永遠に千切れてく お揃いのキーホルダー
Forever tearing apart, our matching keychains
夏が消し去った 白い肌の少女に
To the girl with white skin that summer erased
哀しいほど 取り憑かれてしまいたい
I want to be possessed by you to a sad extent
透明な君は 僕を指差してた
You, transparent, were pointing at me
遂に始まりました！！ボカコレです！！
It's finally started!! It's BocaColle!!
UNO♡
UNO!
おや、手札多過ぎクッソワロタｗ
Oh? Your hand is way too big, LOL
次のターンで私が勝ちまちゅね♡
I'm gonna win on the next turn♡
そのザコさの秘訣を教えてちょ。う・じ・む・し・ちゃん♡
Tell me the secret to that weakness. Lit-tle mag-got-chan♡
ねぇカッコわるく負けちゃだーめっ。
Hey, you mustn't lose so pathetically.
ほら がんばれっ♡がんばれっ♡
Come on, do your best♡ do your best♡
ホンキ出したら勝てるんでしょ早く見せて？一煽り。
If you get serious, you can win, right? Hurry up and show me? One taunt.
屈辱辱辱辱ミス辱
Humiliation-tion-tion-tion miss-tion
此奴は言わずと知れた
This fellow is as you well know
いくじなし♡
A coward♡
ぴえん越えてだったぁ♡
Beyond Pien, it was Tassa♡
ぱおん越えてざっまぁ♡
Beyond Paon, serves you right!♡
さわど されど その場しのぎはー
However, that stopgap measure...
Shhh...
ジャケラ ぴえん越えてざっさー♡
Jakera! Beyond crying, you're a loser! ♡
ぱおん越えてざっまぁ♡
Beyond wailing, serves you right! ♡
ゲームセット！
Game set!
はい！ みむかわナイストライ♡
Yes! Mimukawa Nice Try! ♡
ざぁーこ♡ ざぁーこ♡ ざぁーこ♡ ざぁーこ♡
Loo-ser! ♡ Loo-ser! ♡ Loo-ser! ♡ Loo-ser! ♡
酸性雨に埋まっちゃえ♡
Get buried in acid rain! ♡
ざぁーこ♡ ざぁーこ♡ ざぁーこ♡ ざぁーこ♡
Loo-ser! ♡ Loo-ser! ♡ Loo-ser! ♡ Loo-ser! ♡
33-4
...なんで手札出さねえの？
Why aren't you playing your hand?
ひょっとしてひよってんの？
Are you getting cold feet?
まじくっそだせえな
You're so freaking pathetic.
あ・く・し・ろ・よ。
Hurry. Up. and. Go.
《舌打 ちざござご ASMR》
《Tongue clicking/Za-go-za-go ASMR》
ね、早く出そ？
Hey, hurry up and play it.
もし私に勝ったら この奴の言うことを
If you win against me, I'll do whatever...
なんでも聞いてあげるよ♡
...this person tells me to! ♡
...まあ 勝てないけど♡ (笑)
...Well, not that you could win! ♡ (LOL)
噛ませ犬に抜擢！ よわよわこやつぁ♡
Promoted to underdog! This weakling! ♡
所詮... 先の時代の敗北者♡
After all... just a loser from the previous era! ♡
ジャケラ ぴえん越えてざっさー♡
Jakera! Beyond crying, you're a loser! ♡
ぱおん越えてざっまぁ♡
Beyond wailing, serves you right! ♡
さわど されど その場しのぎは↓
However, that stopgap measure...
Shhh...
ジャケラ ぴえん越えてざっさー♡
Jakera! Beyond crying, you're a loser! ♡
ぱおん越えてざっまぁ♡
Beyond wailing, serves you right! ♡
ゲームセット！
Game set!
はい！ みむかわナイストライ♡
Yes! Mimukawa Nice Try! ♡
ざぁーこ♡ ざぁーこ♡ ざぁーこ♡ ざぁーこ♡
Loo-ser! ♡ Loo-ser! ♡ Loo-ser! ♡ Loo-ser! ♡
酸性雨に埋まっちゃえ♡
Get buried in acid rain! ♡
ざぁーこ♡ ざぁーこ♡ ざぁーこ♡ ざぁーこ♡
Loo-ser! ♡ Loo-ser! ♡ Loo-ser! ♡ Loo-ser! ♡
たわいない最終回 頼るの？
Clinging to a silly series finale?
ざぁーこ♡ ざぁーこ♡ ざぁーこ♡ ざぁーこ♡
Loo-ser! ♡ Loo-ser! ♡ Loo-ser! ♡ Loo-ser! ♡
負けちゃお？♡ 負けちゃお？♡
Wanna lose? ♡ Wanna lose? ♡
ね、みじめに生き恥さらさせちゃお？♡
Hey, wanna be exposed in miserable shame? ♡
出せ 出せ 出せ 出せ 敗北宣言ぶちまけろっ！！
Show it! Show it! Spit out your declaration of defeat!!
(Vocalizing)
ラブと情愛 罰症はないない
Love and affection, no penalties
君だけが毒滅じゃないんだ
You're not the only one who's unique
反省とか私に求められても
Even if you ask me to reflect on myself
本当、病んだり勘違いしないでっ
Seriously, don't get depressed or misunderstand me
どうしてなんで大概の立ち回りは滑るの？
Why does almost every move fall flat?
さいしょに無理やめ時なんて伝えたじゃん
I told you from the start it was impossible, right?
お純情様 散らが手口ですが
My pure-hearted one, being messy is my style
やっぱ 会いたくないのですが
As expected, I don't really want to see you
ハムステ一 ワンモアチャンス
Hamster, one more chance
もうやっぱ びったらびったらいいじゃん
Well, it's fine if it's all messy
ポップなアイブだったらいいじゃん
It's fine if it's a pop-style vibe
みっともないから嫉妬しないでニャ
It's unsightly, so don't be jealous, nya
寂しくなったら誰でもいいじゃん
If you're lonely, anyone will do
生まれればいいじゃん 隣がいいじゃん
It's fine as long as we're born, being next to you is fine
いやいや愛していかなくちゃなんて
No, no, having to love each other...
死ぬまでぴょんぴょんやってんの
...we'll be hopping along until we die
やっぱ びったらびったらいいじゃん
Well, it's fine if it's all messy
バットなダンサーハマったらいいじゃん
It's fine if you fall for a bad dancer
やっぱり好きとかやってらんねーわ
I can't deal with that "I love you" stuff
わかんない明後日そーでー
I don't know, maybe the day after tomorrow
ワンモアチャンス
One more chance
もうやっぱ びったらびったらいいじゃん
Well, it's fine if it's all messy
ポップなアイブだったらいいじゃん
It's fine if it's a pop-style vibe
みっともないから嫉妬しないでニャ
It's unsightly, so don't be jealous, nya
寂しくなったら誰でもいいじゃん
If you're lonely, anyone will do
生まれればいいじゃん 隣がいいじゃん
It's fine as long as we're born, being next to you is fine
いやいや愛してしたくなって
No, no, wanting to love you...
死ぬまでぴょんぴょんやってんの
...we'll be hopping along until we die
やっぱ びったらびったらいいじゃん
Well, it's fine if it's all messy
バットなダンサーハマったらいいじゃん
It's fine if you fall for a bad dancer
やっぱり好きとかやってらんねーわ
I can't deal with that "I love you" stuff
わかんない明後日そーでー
I don't know, maybe the day after tomorrow
寂しくなったら誰でもいいじゃん
If you're lonely, anyone will do.
生まれたてエンジン
Brand-new engine.
いやいや愛して　痛くなって
Love me reluctantly, until it hurts.
こっちからフラれてやってんぞ
I'm the one who's dumping you.
OK!
Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah 悪い子さ
Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah, I'm a bad girl.
Ma Ma Ma Ma おあいこじゃん
Ma Ma Ma Ma, we're even.
Sa Sa Sa Sa 始めるよ
Sa Sa Sa Sa, let's start.
もっとこの穴を愛してよ
Love this hole even more.
Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah 悪い子さ
Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah, I'm a bad girl.
Ma Ma Ma Ma おあいこじゃん
Ma Ma Ma Ma, we're even.
Sa Sa Sa Sa 始めるよ
Sa Sa Sa Sa, let's start.
もっとこの穴を愛してよ
Love this hole even more.
達成
Done!
ビビデバ
Bibideba
つまんない？　散々残念
Boring? Truly disappointing.
奇跡願ってるだけの人生
A life spent just wishing for miracles.
Bite me Do do do do
独り占めまじ
Seriously, keeping it all to myself.
Ad-lib me Free da
もっと Free da
More Free da.
ハイタッチちょっと宇宙待って
High-five, wait a bit in space.
両心は音を立てて
Both hearts making noise.
夜を急かす名もなき野郎
A nameless fellow hurrying the night.
人生は一瞬にして
Life, in an instant...
解ける魔法
...is a spell that breaks.
それならば駆け抜けて　My darling
In that case, let's run through it, My darling.
シャマナバシャトリのステップ
Step on the shamana bashatori.
私は大変身メイクアップ
I'm a major transformation, make-up.
わがままなパニマニきらめきに注中
Absorbed in selfish panimani sparkles.
シャラナバシャセーのサビ
Chorus of sharana bashasay.
さよならグッバイレトロカー
Goodbye, goodbye retro car.
いつかは喝采クラップオーディエンス
One day, an applauding audience.
皆々ご唱和あれ
Everyone, sing along!
こんがらがってもしょうがない
Tangled up, nothing we can do about it.
ガラス手をとってTonight
Taking a glass hand, tonight.
今夜に明日などないならば
If there is no tomorrow tonight...
自由に踊ったもん勝ちでしょ
...then the one who danced freely wins, right?
デ、デ、デ、ダンスライドハリホ
De, de, de, dance slide hariho.
どんな問題も会話ひとつ
Any problem, just one conversation.
白紙も正解も間違いも
A blank page, a correct answer, and a mistake.
愛す本当の私のりさ
Is the real me I love.
なんだか世界は限界の気配がして
Somehow the world feels like it's at its limit...
おっとっと　安心じゃ心配
Whoops, safe but worried.
今すぐジャンピンジャンピンな
Jumping jumping right now.
チキバンバン　チキバンバン　意想楽々に危機快楽
Chiki ban ban, chiki ban ban, leisure in imagination, pleasure in crisis.
指にギリギリ爆発　ギミザダイマ発走してしまおうか
Explosion at the fingertips, shall we start the "give me the dime"?
まだまだビリついた君にアンサー
An answer to you who's still tingling.
一発じゃ足りないわ　ついに導き出した君にアンサー
One shot isn't enough, finally an answer for you that I've derived.
灰になるまで踊ってよ
Dance until you turn to ash!
シャマナバシャトリのステップ
Step on the shamana bashatori.
私は大変身メイクアップ
I'm a major transformation, make-up.
わがままなパニマニきらめきに注中
Absorbed in selfish panimani sparkles.
シャラナバシャセーのサビ
Chorus of sharana bashasay.
さよならグッバイレトロカー
Goodbye, goodbye retro car.
いつかは喝采クラップオーディエンス
One day, an applauding audience.
皆々ご唱和あれ
Everyone, sing along!
こんがらがってもしょうがない
Tangled up, nothing we can do about it.
ガラス手をとってTonight
Taking a glass hand, tonight.
今夜に明日などないならば
If there is no tomorrow tonight...
自由に踊ったもん勝ちでしょ
...then the one who danced freely wins, right?
うわー！
Wah!
素晴らしい！
Wonderful!
ふー！
Phew!
ちょっと足こんがらがっちゃった。
I got my legs a bit tangled up.
こんがらがってもしょうがない。
Tangled up, nothing we can do about that.
はい、ということで、マリンさんお誕生日おめでとうございます！
Yes, and so, Marine-san, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
魔法をかけさせていただきました。
I have cast a spell on you.
本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much!
すごい可愛い！
So cute!
え、可愛いよ。
Eh, you are cute.
17歳みたい。
Like you're 17.
うん、17歳みたい。
Yeah, like you're 17.
いつもよりちょっと若げに、魔法かけておきました。
I cast a spell to make you look a bit younger than usual.
ありがとう！もう年をとったのに若返っちゃうなんて最高の気分！
Thank you! Even though I'm getting older, feeling rejuvenated is the best!
確かに。あ、今年何歳になりました？
True. Oh, how old did you turn this year?
アンチエイジングの化身、ありがとう。
I'm the embodiment of anti-aging. Thank you.
あ、よかったです。
Oh, that's good.
という感じでね。
And like that.
なんと、すいちゃんが来てくれて、この「ビビデバ」を歌わせてもらいました！
Sui-chan actually came and we sang "Bibideba" together!
はい、ありがとうございます、一緒に歌ってくれて。
Yes, thank you for singing with me.
楽しかったね！
It was fun!
なんか衣装もほら、シナジーがあるじゃない。
The outfits also have synergy, don't they?
あ、そうなんだよ。
Ah, that's right.
黒同士でね。
Both in black.
ここら辺ちょっと、マリンカラーが。
And this part has a bit of Marine's color.
もう匂わせですか？
Is this a teaser?
ちょっと匂わせてもらって。
Just teasing a little bit.
ほら、後ろのルビーとなんか色が似てなくない？
Look, isn't the color similar to the ruby in the back?
あ、確かに、確かに。
Ah, true, true.
いい感じ、いい感じ。
Nice, nice.
そんな感じでね、ちょっとレッスンとかもね、一緒にやった話とかをしたいんだけど。
And like that, I wanted to talk about our lessons together.
はい、しましたね。
Yes, we did.
もう、マリンが6時間、いや何時間だろう。
Marine took 6 hours, or how many hours was it...
6時間くらいかけて覚えたところを、すいちゃんが「お疲れ様ですー」30分で覚えて、ガクッ！
The part I spent 6 hours learning, Sui-chan learned in 30 minutes and said "Good job!" I was crushed!
いや、元々私やってたからさ。
Well, I've been doing it for a while now...
確かに、やってて。
True, you have been.
ちょっとその要素を拾いつつ、このマリンの生誕のあのヤツ風にアレンジって感じだったから、
I picked up those elements and arranged them in Marine's birthday style.
ま、ほぼ元のやつを入れてくれてたんで、振付の人。ま、だからできたというわけですよ、すいちゃん！
Basically, the choreographer included the original moves. That's why I could do it, Suisei-san!
マリンさん、そんな、近い近い。
Marine-san, don't get so close.
本番当日になって、マリンが間違えてるところがあって、急に直すことになったりして。
Also, on the day of the show, there was a part Marine got wrong, so we had to fix it suddenly.
そうなんですよ、「待てー」とか言って、「待てー」とか言ってね。
That's right, we were like "Wait!", "Wait!".
ここの足がね、こうやってたんだけど、そう、こうやってたんだけど、
This leg part, I was doing it like this, yeah, like this...
どんどんズレて、こんな状態。映ってるか？ こうやってたんだよね。
It was getting weirder and weirder. Is it on camera? I was doing it like this.
あ、こうやってたんだけど、なんかこうだったんだよね、すいちゃん！
Yeah, like that, but it was actually like this, Suisei-san!
「これじゃあ、へっぴり腰になっちゃう」とか言って、「こうだよ！」「こうやったらへっぴり腰になっちゃう！」もう散々だったんですけど。
"I'll look like a coward with this posture!" "It's like this!" "If I did that, I'd look like a coward!" It was a mess.
でも楽しかったね。
But it was fun.
楽しかったー！ また、すいまり何か...
It was fun! So, SuiMari, what's next...
あ、すいまり何かまた動きが、来年かな？
What's next for SuiMari... next year maybe?
何かあるのかなー？
Is there something coming up?
あるのかな、ちょっと。どうなんだろう。来年は... ここで匂わせてもちょっと遠いけど、来年こそは熱い、すいまり熱いぞ。
I wonder... Hinting at it now is a bit far off, but next year will be hot, SuiMari will be hot.
まあまあ、熱いかな。来年こそは熱いかも。
Well, it might be hot. Next year might be hot indeed.
って感じで、次はなんと、マリン新衣装のお披露目があるんですよ！
And next, I have a new costume reveal!
あー！ そうなんだ！ どんな感じの衣装なのか、ちょっと...
Oh! What kind of costume is it? Just a little...
うわ、ちょっと、ヒントいうとですね、この後の楽曲、超超スペシャルスペシャルスペシャルゲスト、マリンの憧れの人がいらっしゃる。
Well, a little hint... the next song has a super special guest, someone I admire.
おお！ 憧れの人。
Oh! Someone you admire.
ヒント、これです！ これです！
Hint! This! This!
ほうほうほう。あ、なるほど。これです。あ、待って、ちょっとイメージ湧いてきた！
I see, I see. Oh, I see. Wait, I'm getting the image!
あ、なるほど。じゃあ、魔法かけてあげますよ。おっと。
Oh, I see. Then, I'll cast a spell on you. Whoops.
いきますよ！ せーの！
Here we go! One, two...
うわあああ！ 新衣装になっちゃう！ 新衣装になれー！ あ、若返る！ 若返る！
Waaaah! Transform into the new costume! Become the new costume! Ah, I'm getting younger! I'm getting younger!
おい、なんで若返るんだよ。年取ってるみたいだろ。
Hey, why am I getting younger? It sounds like I was old!
引き裂いた　闇が吠え　震える帝都に
In the torn darkness that howls, in the trembling Imperial Capital
愛の歌　高らかに　踊り出る戦士たち
With a song of love raised high, the warriors dance forth
心まで　鋼鉄に　武装する乙女
Maidens who arm even their hearts with steel
悪を蹴散らして　正義を示すのだ
Scattering evil to show our justice
さん、はい！
Three, go!
走れ　光速の　帝国華撃団
Run, at the speed of light, Imperial Assault Force
唸れ　衝撃の　帝国華撃団
Roar, with a shock, Imperial Assault Force
私たち、正義のために戦います。
We fight for the sake of justice.
たとえそれが命を懸ける戦いであっても、
Even if it's a battle that costs us our lives,
私たちは一歩も引きません。
we will not take a single step back.
それが、帝国華撃団なのです！
That is the Imperial Assault Force!
街の灯が　消え果てて　怯える帝都に
In the trembling Imperial Capital where the city lights have faded away
虹の色　染め上げて　踊り出る戦士たち
Painting it in rainbow colors, the warriors dance forth
暁に　激情を　照らし出す乙女
Maidens who illuminate their passion at dawn
悪を滅ぼして　正義を示すのだ
Destroying evil to show our justice
走れ　光速の　帝国華撃団
Run, at the speed of light, Imperial Assault Force
唸れ　衝撃の　帝国華撃団
Roar, with a shock, Imperial Assault Force
もいっかい！
One more time!
走れ　光速の　帝国華撃団
Run, at the speed of light, Imperial Assault Force
唸れ　衝撃の　帝国華撃団
Roar, with a shock, Imperial Assault Force
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
ヨーホーホーホー　ハラヘー
Yo-ho-ho-ho, Hara-he...
マリン出航！！
作詞：畑亜貴　作曲・編曲：田中公平
Marine Shukkou!!
Lyrics: Aki Hata  Composition/Arrangement: Kohei Tanaka
世界が壊れてゆく
The world is breaking apart.
泣き声が聞こえていた
I could hear the voices crying out.
汚れた拳　痛むほど
I clenched my dirty fists...
強く握った
...so hard it hurt.
当たり前に笑っていた昨日はもうどこにもない
The yesterday when we laughed normally is nowhere to be found.
明日がどんな日になるのか誰も知らない
No one knows what kind of day tomorrow will be.
圧政にさえ　捨てられた蝶
A butterfly abandoned even by tyranny...
取り戻すこと誓う
...I swear to take it back.
怒り上げ　勇気の旗掲げて旅立とう
Raise the anchor, hoist the flag of courage, and let's set off.
嵐の海　立ち上がれ
Rise up in the stormy sea.
幸せは願えば手に入るほど安くはない
Happiness is not so cheap that you can get it just by wishing.
守るために戦うなら海賊となればいい
If you're going to fight to protect, then you should become a pirate.
ヨーホーホーホー　ハラヘー
Yo-ho-ho-ho, Hara-he...
幸せ　簡単に愛の中消えてしまう
Happiness easily vanishes within love.
悲鳴をただ見てることが許せないなら
If you can't forgive yourself for just watching people scream...
独りきりで震えていた弱い自分消えはしない
The weak self that trembled alone will not disappear.
それでも決意胸に抱けばもう惑わない
But if you hold resolve in your heart, you won't hesitate anymore.
道半ばで倒れた友に託された言葉抱き
Embracing the words entrusted to me by a friend who fell on the way...
怒り上げ　自由の旗上げて突き進め
Raise the anchor, hoist the flag of freedom, and charge forward.
大海原　燃え上がれ
Blaze up in the vast ocean.
どんな運命だろうとも消えることなきこの唸れ
No matter what destiny awaits, let this roar never fade.
怒り上げ　勇気の旗掲げて旅立とう
Raise the anchor, hoist the flag of courage, and let's set off.
嵐の海　立ち上がれ
Rise up in the stormy sea.
幸せは願えば手に入るほど安くはない
Happiness is not so cheap that you can get it just by wishing.
守るために戦うなら海賊となればいい
If you're going to fight to protect, then you should become a pirate.
ヨーホーホーホー　ハラヘー
Yo-ho-ho-ho, Hara-he...
ホーホーヘー　ホーホーヘー　ヨーホーホーヘー
Ho-ho-he, Ho-ho-he, Yo-ho-ho-he...
恐れずにここで暁の勝利のために立ち上がれ
Fearlessly rise up here for the victory of the dawn.
ヨーホーホーホー　ハラヘー
Yo-ho-ho-ho, Hara-he...
ホーホーヘー　ホーホーヘー　ヨーホーホーヘー
Ho-ho-he, Ho-ho-he, Yo-ho-ho-he...
独りきりいつか集まればやがて偉大なる海賊団だ
When those who were alone gather, we'll become a great pirate crew.
いかりあげー　出航！！
Raise the anchor— Set sail!!
はい！というわけで、なんと横山智佐さんに来ていただきました！
Alright! And so, we have the one and only Chisa Yokoyama here with us!
はい、ろしくお願いします。
Yes, thank you for having me.
お願いします。あ、ちょっと改めて自己紹介をしていただいてもよろしいでしょうか？
Thank you. Oh, could I ask you to introduce yourself once again?
もちろんです。帝国華撃団・花組、真宮寺さくらです！
Of course. I'm Sakura Shinguji of the Imperial Assault Force, Flower Division!
と演じ続けて29年目になっています、横山智佐です！
And I'm Chisa Yokoyama, now in my 29th year of playing the role!
きゅ～！すごい！
Kyan! Amazing!
マリンさんお誕生日おめでとうございます！
Marine-san, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！本当に...
Thank you so much! Truly...
もう超感動です。
I'm so moved.
マリンはもうめちゃめちゃサクラ大戦大好きで、
Marine loves Sakura Wars so much,
サクラ大戦愛し続けてはや20…20数年って感じで、
I've been loving Sakura Wars for over 20... 20-some years now,
なっておりまして。
and here I am.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
もう、本当、その思いで…
With those feelings...
ずっと前から横山智佐さんと、
ever since a long time ago, I've wanted to...
一緒に歌えたらって思い続けて、
sing together with Chisa Yokoyama-san.
ついに、ついに、ついに念願が叶いました！
Finally, finally, my long-cherished wish has come true!
はい、強い愛をありがとうございます。
Yes, thank you for your strong love.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
本当にめちゃめちゃ嬉しいです。
I'm really, really happy.
こちらこそ。
Me too.
ということで今回、選曲がですね…
So, about the setlist this time...
まあもう当たり前なんですけど、
well, it's obvious, but...
横山智佐さんに来ていただいたら、
with Chisa Yokoyama-san here,
『激帝』歌うしか絶対ないということで、
there's no choice but to sing "GekiTei".
『激帝』一緒に歌わせていただきました。
We sang "GekiTei" together.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございました。
さらに、マリンのオリジナル曲の…
Furthermore, for Marine's original song...
『マリン出航』も一緒に歌っていただいちゃいました。
"Marine's Departure," you sang it with me too!
田中公平先生ですね。
That's Tanaka Kouhei-sensei, right?
そうなんです。
That's right.
公平先生メドレーにしまして。
We made it a Tanaka Kouhei-sensei medley.
ええ。
Yes.
もうやっぱり公平先生の歌をね、
Since you've been singing...
ずっと歌い続けていらっしゃるので、
Tanaka Kouhei-sensei's songs for a long time,
やっぱ横山智佐さん、
naturally, Chisa Yokoyama-san,
ばっちり、超合ってました。
it was a perfect, amazing match.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
もう公平先生の曲はたくさん歌ってきたんですけど、
I've sung many of Kouhei-sensei's songs, but...
こんなに練習して臨んだの、久しぶりです。
it's been a long time since I've practiced this much.
え、そうなんですか？
Wait, really?
え、なんでですか？
Eh, why is that?
いや、なんか振りとか…
Well, the choreography and things like that...
あ、はい。
Ah, yes.
かっこいいニュアンスとか、可愛らしいマリンちゃんの声とか、
the cool nuances, and Marine-chan's cute voice,
いろんなものを邪魔しないように…
I tried not to get in the way of everything...
いやいやいや！何とんでもないですよ！
No, no, no! That's absurd!
とんでもない。
Not at all.
いや、マリンも、もう横山智佐さんと一緒に『激帝』…
No, Marine was also like, "Singing 'GekiTei' with her..."
マリンが邪魔だと思って、
I thought *I* was the one in the way.
とんでもない。
Not at all.
もうサビなんて、もうハモっちゃいましたもん。下で。
In the chorus, I even ended up harmonizing in the low part.
下でハモリに行っちゃいましたよ、もう。
I went to sing the lower harmony, really.
ありがとうございます。でも愛があればね、お互いにね。
Thank you. But if there's love, for both of us.
はい、愛で、すごい素敵な歌になったと思います。
Yes, with love, I think it became a wonderful song.
そしてね、えっと、このね…
And, well, this...
ほら、ステージがね、変わったのお気づきですか？皆さん。
look, the stage has changed, did everyone notice?
ええ、もうやっぱりね、
Yeah, naturally,
横山智佐さん来ていただきましたので、『サクラ大戦』って感じで。
since she's here, we went with a "Sakura Wars" feel.
ええ、すごーい！
Wow, amazing!
和風、サクラなステージになりました。
It's become a Japanese-style, sakura-filled stage.
ありがとうございます。なんかジャ～とか出て…
Thank you. There was like a "whoosh" sound...
そうそうそう。水がザバーって。
Right, right. Water splashing.
ええ、ジャ～って出たりとか。
Yeah, it came out with a "whoosh".
おー！すごいすごい。
Oh! Amazing, amazing.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
すごいねー。
It's incredible.
和な雰囲気。
A Japanese atmosphere.
お客さん、びしょびしょになってないですかね？
Aren't the audience members getting soaked?
いや、いいんじゃないですか。海賊なんで、マリンはね。
Well, it should be fine. Marine is a pirate, after all.
ああ、そうですね。
Ah, that's true.
ファンもみんな海賊なんで、こんな感じでびしょびしょにしていきましょう。
The fans are all pirates, so let's get them soaked.
そしてね、もう…
And also...
もう背景に溶け込んでますけど、触れないといけません。
it's blending into the background, but I have to mention it.
なんとね、光武が！
Believe it or not, a Koubu!
すごーい！
Amazing!
光武が！
A Koubu!
わー！かっこいい！
Wow! So cool!
すげー！
Incredible!
もう感動、光武が。マジで？
I'm so moved, a Koubu. For real?
光武…
Koubu...
光武、上手だったね。
Koubu was good at it.
ダンス、そうなんです、そうなんです。
The dancing, yes, exactly.
『激帝』もね、一緒にね、踊っちゃいました、こうやってね。
It even danced "GekiTei" together with us like this.
もう、本当にありがとうございます。
Really, thank you so much.
すごいですよ。だって光武は…
It's amazing. Because for the Koubu,
マジでダメもとで、
I really asked just in case,
うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah.
まあ、もう無理だろうなと思いながら、
thinking it would probably be impossible,
「光武と一緒に踊ったり…」ってダメもとでちょっと確認してみたら、
but I asked, "Could I dance with a Koubu..."
なんと来てくださいました。
and believe it or not, it came here!
すごーい、ありがとう光武。
Amazing, thank you, Koubu.
わー、すごい。超感動、ありがとうございます。
Wow, incredible. I'm so moved, thank you very much.
本当に、SEGAさんありがとうございます。
Really, thank you so much, SEGA.
願えばね。
If you wish for it.
そう、願えば叶うということで。
Right, if you wish, it'll come true.
そしてね、衣装も。
And also, the costume.
わー、可愛いですね。
Wow, it's cute.
いや、ちょっと横山さんもすごい…
No, yours is also amazing, Yokoyama-san...
だって、ご覧ください。
I mean, please take a look.
マリンもですけど、ちょっと先に横山さんいいですか。
I'm wearing one too, but let's look at hers first.
ほら、もうサクラです！
Look, it's Sakura!
ええ、サクラ柄にしました。
Yes, I went with a sakura pattern.
わー、サクラ柄素敵。
Wow, the sakura pattern is lovely.
すごい、もうリボンもね、ちゃんとパシッと立ってて。
Incredible, and the ribbon is perfectly upright too.
多分いつもの衣装だと、なんかすごくキラキラなので、
I think if it were the usual costume, it'd be sparkly,
あ、そうですよね。
Ah, that's true.
なんかすごいことになってしまうと思って、
so I thought it might be a bit too much,
なんか、はい、はいからさんな雰囲気のサクラにしました。
and I went with a "Haikara-san" style Sakura.
めちゃめちゃ超々素敵です。
It's incredibly, extremely wonderful.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
いつものステージの歌謡ショウのね、サクラさんの衣装って…
Usually, the Sakura-san costume from the Kayou Show...
結構スパンコールみたいでキラキラキラキラって…
has lots of sequins and is all sparkly...
そうですね。
That's true.
なってるんですよね、全体的に。
all over, generally.
ええ、でもそちらのね、はいからさんな感じも超々最高で。
Yeah, but that "Haikara-san" feel is also the best.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
そしてマリンも合わせました、ジャン！
And Marine matched her too, Ta-da!
着物で合わせてきましたよ。
I matched you with a kimono.
わー、これね、初お披露目の新衣装となっておりまーす。
Wow, this is the debut of my new costume!
ルーズソックス、可愛い。
The loose socks are cute.
そうなんです。分かりますか？
That's right. Can you tell?
ちょっとね、何て言うか…
A little bit, how should I say...
はいからな感じで。
it has a "haikara" feel.
えー、この衣装ね、このルーズソックスな部分も見ていただくと…
With this costume, if you look at the loose socks part too,
感じるかもしれないです、和洋ミックスで。
you might feel it, the Japanese-Western mix.
ここからね、さらに…
From here, furthermore...
大きな差分というか、衣装のね、
there's a big variation, or rather, in the costume,
違いがあるんです、なんと。
there's a difference, believe it or not.
はい。
Yes.
ちょっと脱いだりもできて、これからお披露目するんですけど。
I can take some layers off, and I'll be showing it soon.
はい、楽しみですね。
Yes, looking forward to it.
ありがとうございます。また後でちょっと見ていてください。
Thank you. Please take a look later on.
たぶんお披露目します、ジャン！
I'll probably show it off, Ta-da!
ちょっと羨ましいのは、
What's a bit enviable is,
手を上げても肘とか出ないのが嬉しい。
I'm glad your elbows don't show when you raise your hands.
ごめんなさいね、私、今こうなってるときに肘全開になっちゃって。
Sorry, for me right now, my elbows are completely exposed.
落ちちゃいますよね、これね。
They tend to slide down, don't they?
ええ、もう。
Yeah, really.
そうなんですよ。
That's true.
夢がある。
It's like a dream.
そう、夢がある、あるんですよ。
Right, it's like a dream, it really is.
そして、ちょっとせっかくなんですが、
And, since we have the chance,
横山智佐さんに来ていただいて…
with Chisa Yokoyama-san here...
ちょっとやっぱりマリンの大好きな、真宮寺さくらのセリフとか…
I'd really like a line from my beloved Shinguji Sakura...
ちょっとだけ、もらいたいなーって…
Just a little bit, if I could...
全然！じゃあ「食らっちゃいな！」でやります。
Of course! Then I'll do "Kuracchai na!" (Eat this!).
いいんですか！？
Are you sure!?
はい、「食らっちゃいな！」
Yes, "Kuracchai na!"
やー！ありがとうございます。
Yay! Thank you very much.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
行きます。はい、お願いします。
Here I go. Yes, please.
破邪剣聖…
Haja Kensei...
桜花放神！！
Ohka Houshin!!
すごーい！！
Amazing!!
光武も決めポーズして… これ放ってる、放ってるよー！わあ最高。
Kobu is also doing a pose... It's really firing, it's firing! Wow, the best.
マリンはね、もうこのさくらさんのこの… 破邪剣聖桜花放神の、この声の圧が大好きで。
Marine just loves this... this power in Sakura-san's voice for Haja Kensei Ohka Houshin.
もうこんな格好良く必殺技のセリフ言われる人いませんよってくらい超超格好いいです本当に。
There's really no one else who can say special move lines as cool as this. It's super, super cool.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
広井王子さんが、他のアニメで叫んでるのを聞いて「これだ」と思ったらしいですね。
Apparently, Hiroi Oji-san heard you shouting in another anime and thought, "This is it."
そうですよね、インタビューで見ました。
That's right, I saw that in an interview.
初めてスタジオで破邪剣聖桜花放神を収録したときには、マイクが振り切ってしまって…
When you first recorded Haja Kensei Ohka Houshin in the studio, the mic maxed out...
スタジオの中、斜め向こうを向いて、全然マイクと口全然合ってないじゃんっていう方向で収録しました。
You recorded looking diagonally away in the studio, in a direction where the mic and mouth didn't match at all.
割れないようにですね！そのくらいのすごい圧がバーッて、バーッて出てるんですよ。
So it wouldn't distort! That much incredible power was just bursting out of you.
最高、最高の必殺技ですからね。本当にありがとうございます。
It's the best, the ultimate special move. Thank you so much.
ありがとうございます。マリンさんの一つ一つに本当に強い愛を感じて幸せです。
Thank you. I feel a really strong love in everything you say, Marine-san, and I'm happy.
もう大好きなんです！まだまだ語りたい！もう時間よ止まれ、まだ言いたいことがたくさんあるんですけど…
I love it so much! I want to talk more! Time, please stop, I still have so much to say...
うわあどうしよう、まだ言いたいことたくさんあるけど、そろそろ締めないと。
Oh no, what should I do? I still have so much to say, but I have to wrap this up.
マリンもね、この後もライブまだ続きますので。
Marine's live will still continue after this.
応援します！
I'll support you!
いやー、まだ語りたいけど… いやだ終わりたくない…
Man, I want to talk more... No, I don't want it to end...
夢の続きということで… 全国の大神隊長に、敬礼一緒にさせていただいて…
As a continuation of the dream... let's salute Captain Ogami nationwide together...
いや、マリンじゃないな。これは横山さんに言っていただきたいです。
Actually, not Marine. I'd like Yokoyama-san to say it.
はい。じゃあ全国の大神中尉と、そしてマリンファンの皆様へ… 敬礼！
Okay. Then, to Lieutenant Ogami nationwide, and to all the Marine fans... Salute!
ありがとうございましたー！！幸せー！！うわあー、終わらないでー！！
Thank you so much!! I'm so happy!! Wow, don't let it end!!
ハッピー 羨めば悲惨の香
Happy, if you're envious, it's the scent of misery
アンラッキー 人なら誰しも
Unlucky, everyone is human
ビーハッピー 傍目も振らせよ
Be happy, don't let others distract you
イッサイガッサイ 劣等新世
Everything and anything, the new age of inferiority
むせ返るような過去も
The past that makes you choke
退屈な未来も
The boring future, too
カウンセリング やれやれそこどけ ピーチピチ
Counseling, good grief, get out of the way, peach-pichi
UNDEAD
作詞・作曲：Ayase
Lyrics & Music: Ayase
ハッピー
Happy
アンラッキー
Unlucky
ビーハッピー
Be happy
アレダコレダ
That and this
ねえねえねえ なんだかどうして 戦ってるようなそんな気がすんの
Hey, hey, hey, why does it feel like I'm fighting somehow?
触れられない 誰かとかもな
Someone I can't touch, and others too
過去の自分 自分 じる 自分
My past self, self, my self
とうの昔に死んでる 透明な亡霊と対峙
Confronting a transparent ghost that died long ago
痛いって出て 痛い記憶の奥
It says it hurts, deep inside painful memories
さあね
Well, now
もういないのに あれ
Even though they're gone, huh?
そっちがいい愛のにね
That side is better, even though there's love there
ふっと射されてるのは 今の自分自身よ
The one suddenly being targeted is your current self
チェンジ 見えないふりしてる
Change, pretending not to see
言えなーわコンプレックス
My unspeakable complex
何かに憑かれてるみたい
Like I'm possessed by something
街に出たまま まだ離れられない
Still can't leave even after going out to the city
ありし日の自分
My former self
アンデッド 死んじゃいない
Undead, I'm not dead
お前とお前のレースだ
It's a race between you and you
生きてることと変わり続けられることさ
It's about living and being able to keep changing
不当に思って満足するのよ
Think it's unfair and be satisfied
幸せになろうとしなくたっていいのよ
It's fine even if you don't try to be happy
この世この夜は ギカイギカイファンタジー
This world, this night, is a strange, strange fantasy
次はなにが出るか 怖がってるか
Are you afraid of what will come out next?
出会えあえあえさあ 始まる物語
Meet them, and now, the story begins
人も化け物も さあ猛獣急行便
Humans and monsters too, come on, beast express
5 4 3 2 1 ジャンジャンザバイ
5 4 3 2 1 Jan Jan the bye
5 4 3 2 1 ナウフォーザフューチャー
5 4 3 2 1 Now for the future
たたたたい なんかこうして 未完成に思えちゃうのね
Ta-ta-ta-tai, somehow it feels incomplete like this, doesn't it?
予防もない 完璧なような気がして
No prevention, feeling like it's perfect
もう吸い寄せてる デジャブテンプレで食傷
Already attracting them, bored of the déjà vu templates
素敵な出来事の気配もなくちゃね
There must be a sign of something wonderful
そんで実体験のいい
So, a good actual experience
関係がされた神話と退屈な進化
The myths that were related and the boring evolution
呼ばせ描きが欲しいんだ 飽きちゃったな
I want a description, I've gotten tired of it
慣れちゃったな
I've gotten used to it
脳外科となっていくガイダンス 増えるコンプライアンス
Guidance turning into neurosurgery, increasing compliance
ふっと射されてみたい 収縮して
I want to be suddenly shot, contracting
あれもこれもどれも 同じ味がする
That, this, and even that, they all taste the same
アンデッド 死んじゃいない お前とお前のレースだ
Undead, I'm not dead, it's a race between you and you
いつの夜も過去も未来も 今にあるな
Any night, past or future, they all exist in the now
生きていることを 愚直に果たせよ 目指せハッピーエンド
Perform the act of living honestly, aim for a happy ending
アンデッド 死んじゃいない お前に言ってるんだ
Undead, I'm not dead, I'm talking to you
幸せをきらめかせてしまうのよ お礼だ
Make happiness sparkle, it's a reward
ただ苦しみに慣れて 耐えているだけじゃ
If you're just getting used to suffering and enduring it
死んでるも同然だ 屍の上のアンデッド
You might as well be dead, an undead on top of a corpse
ハッピー 羨めば悲惨の香
Happy, if you're envious, it's the scent of misery
アンラッキー 人なら誰しも
Unlucky, everyone is human
ビーハッピー 傍目も振らせよ
Be happy, don't let others distract you
イッサイガッサイ 劣等新世
Everything and anything, the new age of inferiority
不幸に浸るも
Even soaking in misfortune
幸せになるのもさ
Or becoming happy
全部全部 お前次第だぜ
It's all, all up to you
怨嗟混濁 全財一切合切
Grudge and chaos, everything and all
森羅万象 ピースピースピース
All of creation, peace peace peace
Rise And Fugue Down For The Future
汚れた所に棲むわ言
Idle talk that lives in dirty places
夢幻語り
Tales of fantasy
剥き出しこの化物
This exposed monster
バーチャルのもの語り
A virtual tale
雑魚雑魚雑魚雑魚
Loser, loser, loser, loser
下らない存在 哀れだね
A worthless existence, how pitiful
雑魚雑魚雑魚雑魚 雑魚雑魚雑魚雑魚
Loser, loser, loser, loser, loser, loser, loser, loser
雑魚の雑魚攻撃 効かないよ
A loser's weak attack won't work
雑魚
Loser
Zako (Loser)
作詞・作曲：柊マグネタイト
Composition/Lyrics: Hiiragi Magnetite
雑魚雑魚 雑魚雑魚
Loser, loser, loser, loser
弱弱しすぎる雑魚 本当雑魚
A loser far too weak, truly a loser
雑魚過ぎて論外
So much of a loser, you're out of the question
雑魚雑魚言われたいの？ 変態じゃん
Do you want to be called a loser? You're a pervert
雑魚
Loser
情けない雑魚 かわいそう
A miserable loser, how pathetic
雑魚
Loser
バカにされたいお年頃で
At that age where you want to be mocked
雑魚
Loser
よしよししてあげようか
Shall I comfort you?
目があったね ドキドキしてるんだ
Our eyes met, your heart is racing
何想像してるの？ 超キモいんだけど
What are you imagining? It's super gross
悔しい
Frustrating
なにそのクソ雑魚
What's with that piece of trash loser?
最底辺 弱弱ゴミ
The absolute bottom, weak trash
けど本当は 好き好きめっちゃ好き 嘘です
But actually, I love you so much... Just kidding
かわいいね
How cute
変態
Pervert
雑魚雑魚 雑魚雑魚
Loser, loser, loser, loser
どうせ暇なんでしょ 構ってよ
You're bored anyway, right? Give me some attention
雑魚過ぎて論外
So much of a loser, you're out of the question
幸せ家帰っても 一人でしょ
Even if you go home happy, you're all alone, right?
雑魚
Loser
情けない雑魚 かわいそう
A miserable loser, how pathetic
雑魚
Loser
どうしようもない変態です
A hopeless pervert
雑魚
Loser
いい子いい子してあげようか
Shall I pat your head?
目があったね ドキドキしてるんだ
Our eyes met, your heart is racing
何興奮してんの？ 超キモいんだけど
What are you getting excited for? It's super gross
悔しい
Frustrating
なにそのクソ雑魚
What's with that piece of trash loser?
最底辺 弱弱ゴミ
The absolute bottom, weak trash
けど本当は 好き好きめっちゃ好き 嘘です
But actually, I love you so much... Just kidding
かわいいね
How cute
なにちょっと無視しないで
Hey, don't ignore me
謝るからもう置いていかないで
I'll apologize, so don't leave me behind anymore
あたしのこと嫌いになってないよね
You haven't come to hate me, have you?
信じてる
I believe in you
なにそのクソ雑魚
What's with that piece of trash loser?
すぐ弱弱ゴミ
Just a weak piece of trash
ああ本当は してしてしたい癖に
Ah, though really you want to do it so badly
残念
Too bad
変態
Pervert
夜に浮かんでいた
Floating in the night
海月のような月が爆ぜた
A moon like a jellyfish burst
バス停の背を覗けば
Peeking over the back of the bus stop
あの夏の君が頭にいる
You from that summer are in my head
ただ君に晴れ
Cloudless (Tada Kimi ni Hare)
作詞・作曲：n-buna
Composition/Lyrics: n-buna
鳥居 乾いた雲
Torii gate, parched clouds
夏の匂いが頬を撫でる
The scent of summer brushes my cheek
大人になるまで
Until I become an adult
ほら、背伸びしたままで
Look, as you remain on your tiptoes
遊び疲れたら
When you're tired of playing
バス停裏で空でも見よう
Let's look at the sky behind the bus stop
じきに夏が暮れても
Even if summer soon draws to a close
きっと、きっと覚えてるから
I'm sure, I'm sure I'll remember
追いつけないまま大人になって
Becoming an adult without being able to catch up
君のポケットに夜が咲く
Night blooms in your pocket
口に出せないなら僕は一人だ
If I can't put it into words, I am alone
それでいいから、もう諦めてる
That's fine, I've already given up
だけ
Just...
夏日、乾いた雲
Summer day, dried clouds
揺らめく寂びた標識
Mountains wavering, a rusted sign
記憶の中はいつも
Inside my memories, there's always
夏の匂いがする
The smell of summer
写真なんて紙切れだ
Photographs are just scraps of paper
思い出なんてただのゴミだ
Memories are just garbage
それがわからないから
Since I don't understand that
口を噤んだまま
While remaining silent
耐えず君の移香
Constantly, your fragrance
記憶に夏野の石一つ
In my memory, a single stone in a summer field
俯いたまま大人になって
Becoming an adult with my head down
追いつけない、ただ君に晴れ
Unreachable, just sunny to you
口に出せないまま坂を上った
I climbed the slope without putting it into words
僕らの影に夜が咲いていく
Night begins to bloom in our shadows
俯いたまま大人になった
Became an adult with my head down
君が思うまま手を叩け
Clap your hands as you wish
日の落ちる坂道を上って
Climbing up the slope where the sun sets
僕らの影は
Our shadows are...
追いつけないまま大人になって
Becoming an adult without being able to catch up
君のポケットに夜が咲く
Night blooms in your pocket
口に出せなくても僕ら一つだ
Even if we can't put it into words, we are one
それでいいから、もう
That's fine, so already...
君の想いを噛み締めてる
I'm reflecting on your feelings
だけ
Just...
スキスキ超Dieスキ Ayeシテル
Love-Love Super Die-Love Aye-Shiteru
このあとミュージックビデオ公開！
Music video out right after this!
君たち！船長のことを呼び止めて！
You guys! Call out to the Captain!
精一杯、整列！わかったら返事ね！
With all your might, line up! Answer me if you understand!
キミたちみんなパイレーツ♡ Ahoy!! You're All Pirates♡
You're All Pirates♡ Ahoy!! You're All Pirates♡
Blu-ray発売決定！
Blu-ray release confirmed!
Ahoy! 君排！行きますよー！
Ahoy! Kimi-pai! Here we go!
声をあげて出航だ！
Raise your voice, it's time to set sail!
我ら宝鐘海賊団！
We are the Houshou Pirates!
コンパス片手に旗を掲げ
With a compass in hand, we raise our flag
この海をジャックしちゃうぞ！
We're gonna jack this sea!
ヨーソローついておいで
Steady as she goes, follow me
共にヨーホー！ヨーホー！叫ぼう
Let's shout Yo-ho! Yo-ho! together
嗚呼、最高の日々
Ah, the greatest days
境界線などない
There are no boundaries
宝鐘海賊団！
Houshou Pirates!
それでは行きますよー！出航ーー！！
Well then, here we go! Set sail!!
2日目だー！
It's Day 2!
立ち上がれ 幸せは願えば
Rise up! Happiness, if you wish for it...
手に入るほど安くない
It isn't cheap enough to just fall into your hands
揺るがない守るために戦え
Unwavering, fight to protect
なればいい
If only I could be
開花して！
Blossom!
出航！
Setting sail!
大好き
I love you all.
なんと、宝鐘マリン 1st Live『Ahoy!! 君たちみんなパイレーツ』の
Incredible news! The Blu-ray for Houshou Marine's 1st Live
Blu-rayが、本日21時から受注販売スタートです！
"Ahoy!! You're All Pirates!" starts pre-orders tonight at 9 PM!
ライブに来てくれた君たちも、来られなかった君たちも、ぜひぜひチェックしてくださいね！
Whether you attended the live or couldn't make it,
please be sure to check it out!
そして気になるBlu-rayの収録内容はこちら！
And here are the exciting contents of the Blu-ray!
Day1は歌謡祭がテーマ、
Day 1 is themed around a song festival,
Day2は航海と宝探しをテーマにした超豪華なセットリストになっています。
and Day 2 features a super-extravagant setlist
themed on voyaging and treasure hunting.
現地で君たちの声が聞けて、
Hearing your voices in person there...
船長、本当に元気をもらいました。ありがとうございます。
it really gave me so much energy. Thank you so much.
このBlu-rayがあれば、いつでも君たちの声を聞けるんですね。嬉しい！
With this Blu-ray, I can hear your voices anytime. I'm so happy!
君たちも、いつでも船長の声、聞いてて。
And you guys can listen to my voice anytime too.
続いては、封入特典のご紹介！
Next, let's look at the included bonuses!
特製ブックレット、マリン船長からのお手紙、
A special booklet, a letter from Captain Marine,
ライブ音源レコード、メッセージ入りフォトの4種類が、特典として封入されています。
a live audio record, and a photo with a message
are all included as bonuses.
なんかレコードが特典って、めっちゃ歌謡祭っぽくないですか？
Doesn't having a record as a bonus feel totally like a song festival?
ちなみにこのレコードには、Day2の『マリン出航！！』と
By the way, this record contains the live audio of
『パイパイ仮面でどーかしらん？』のライブ音源を収録してます。
"Marine Shukko!!" and "I'm Your Treasure Box" from Day 2.
お手紙とメッセージ入りフォトは、届いてからのお楽しみです！
The letter and the photo with a message
are surprises for when they arrive!
愛を込めて書きますので、絶対ゲットしてくださいね！
I'll write them with love, so please make sure to get them!
Blu-rayはこの後、21時から受付開始です。
Orders for the Blu-ray start later today at 9 PM.
詳しくは公式X、販売サイト、公式特設サイトをご確認ください！
Please check official X, the sales site, and the official special site for details!
そしてなんと、ライブグッズの再販も決定しました！
And believe it or not, we've decided to resell the live goods too!
最近船長にハマった！って方や、ゲットし損ねた！っていう方はぜひ！
If you've recently become a fan or missed out before, now's your chance!
詳細は公式Xで案内するので、君たち楽しみに待ってて下さい。
Details will be on official X, so look forward to it!
続いて、宝鐘マリン 生誕記念グッズ 2025をご紹介します！
Next, let me introduce the Houshou Marine Birthday Memorial Goods 2025!
今回は最近流行りの『hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME』でも使い勝手のいいグッズセットになっています。
This time, it's a goods set that's very handy for the
popular "hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME."
カードゲームを始めたいけど備品がない方や、
For those who want to start card games but lack supplies,
これを機に更新したい方はぜひ。カードしない方でも使えるグッズばかりなので、ゲットしてください。
or want to refresh their gear, this is for you.
Even if you don't play, these items are still great!
まずはこちら！
First up is this!
フルサイズラバーマットです！
The Full-Size Rubber Mat!
こちらはあかさあい先生描き下ろしで、
This features a new illustration by Akasa Ai-sensei,
ソロライブの衣装で新髪型のバチバチアイドルなマリンになってます。
showing Marine as a cool idol in her solo live outfit
with a new hairstyle.
カードゲームするのにぴったりな、丸めて持ち運びやすい薄手タイプです。
It's a thin type that's easy to roll up and carry around,
perfect for playing card games.
普通に机に敷いて使うのも、とても良い。
It's also great to just use as a desk mat.
次はこちら！
Next is this!
カードスリーブです！
Card Sleeves!
古澤あつし先生の描き下ろし、超美麗新衣装イラスト！
A gorgeous new outfit illustration by Furuzawa Atsushi-sensei!
カードをこの中にしまって綺麗に保護しましょう。
Put your cards in these to protect them beautifully.
ここでしか手に入らないスリーブなので、カードゲームするときちょっと特別感出せますね。
Since these sleeves are exclusive to this set,
they'll make your games feel a bit more special.
続いてはこちら！
Continuing on, we have this!
マリ箱デッキケースです！
The Mari-Box Deck Case!
船長が閉じ込められていた『マリ箱』をイメージしたケースです。
A case designed to look like the "Mari-Box"
that I was once trapped in.
ホロカのデッキが綺麗に収まるベストサイズ。カードしない方も、あらゆる小物入れにちょうどいいですよ。
It's the perfect size for a Hololive card deck.
It also makes a great container for small items!
そして次はこちら！
And next is this!
船長描き下ろしの、フィギュアカードスタンドです！
The Figure Card Stand, drawn by me!
船長が描いたイラストを元に、フィギュア作ってもらいました！
I had this figure made based on my own illustration!
自分の絵が立体になるの初めてだから、ドキドキします。
It's my first time having my art become 3D,
so it's very exciting.
隣の一味くんはアクリルになっていて、カードを挟める設計ですよ。
The Ichimi-kun next to me is an acrylic piece
designed to hold a card.
カード以外にもメモを挟んだりもできますし、
You can also use it to hold memos or other things.
シンプルに船長の描いた絵が初めて立体になったので、記念にゲットしてください。
Since it's the first 3D version of my art,
please get it as a keepsake.
最後にフルセット購入特典のご紹介です。
Lastly, the bonus for purchasing the full set.
数量限定で、直筆メッセージ書かせていただきます。
In limited quantities, I will be writing handwritten messages.
数量限定がなくなったら、箔押し複製メッセージになるんですが、
Once the limited ones are gone, it will be a foil-stamped copy,
こちらもものすごいたっぷりメッセージ書いてるので、ぜひゲットしてください。
but I've written a ton of messages on those too,
so please get them.
そして、生誕記念のフルセットを1点ご購入につき、
And for every purchase of the Birthday Memorial Full Set,
『hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME』のPRカード1枚付いてきます！
you'll receive one PR card for the "hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME"!
生誕記念のあかさあい先生描き下ろしのキービジュアルの
It's a limited PR card featuring Akasa Ai-sensei's
イラストを使用した限定PRカードになります。
key visual illustration for the birthday memorial.
ホロカのテーマにぴったりな、アイドル感満載イラストなので、絶対ゲットしてくださいね！
It's an illustration full of idol charm, perfect for the card game.
Be sure to get it!
さあ、このグッズを手に入れて、
Now, for those of you thinking of getting these goods
ホロカ始めてみようかな？と思ったそこの君！
and starting the card game...
8月29日にマリンのスタートデッキが発売されます！
Marine's Start Deck will be released on August 29th!
これを機に始めてみませんか？
Why not take this chance to start?
そして次の日...
And the next day...
ホロカフェス 2025 サマースペシャル
8月30日(土) 幕張メッセ
HoloCard Fest 2025 Summer Special
August 30 (Sat), Makuhari Messe
8月30日の土曜日には
On Saturday, August 30th,
幕張メッセでホロカフェス2025サマースペシャルが開催されます。
HoloCard Fest 2025 Summer Special will be held at Makuhari Messe.
当日、マリンのアナウンスやスペシャルの映像も流れますよ。
On the day, there will be announcements by Marine and special videos played.
みんなで盛り上がるホロカフェスサマースペシャル、
HoloCard Fest Summer Special, where everyone gets excited,
8月30日お楽しみに。
please look forward to August 30th.
宝鐘マリン 8月29日(金) 発売!!
Houshou Marine, releasing August 29 (Fri)!!
さらに何と今後マリンの描いたイラストがホロカになると言う噂が。
Furthermore, there's a rumor that illustrations drawn by Marine will become HoloCards in the future.
君たちお楽しみに。
You guys, look forward to it.
ぺこまり体操 8月2日～8月16日 毎朝7時
PekoMari Exercise, August 2 - August 16, every morning at 7:00
そして先日も告知しましたが、
Also, as announced the other day,
8月2日朝7時から毎朝2週間、
for two weeks starting August 2nd at 7 AM every morning,
ぺこまりでぺこまり体操を行います。
PekoMari will be doing PekoMari Exercise.
VRC内で行うので3Dでわちゃわちゃやります。
It will be held within VRC, so we'll be messing around in 3D.
ホロメンが来るか来ないか。
Will other Holo-members show up or not?
ぺこまりは二人とも起きられるのか。
Will both of PekoMari be able to wake up?
ま、まずはぺこらとマリンが二人揃うのを願ってます。
Well, first I'm hoping Pekora and Marine both show up together.
このあと 21:30~ メンバーシップ限定ミニLIVE & 撮影会
After this at 21:30~, Membership-only Mini LIVE & Photo Session
というわけで、マリンの生誕ライブを見てくださってありがとうございました。
Anyway, thank you for watching Marine's birthday live.
今回のライブの選曲や裏話など
I'll be talking about the song selection and behind-the-scenes stories of this live
明日の振り返り配信にお話しするのでぜひ来てください。
in tomorrow's review stream, so please come by.
新衣装の推し3Dもお見せしますよ。
I'll also show you the new outfit's 3D assets.
本当に思い出深いライブになりました。
It became a truly memorable live.
君たち繰り返し見てくださいね。
You guys, please watch it over and over again.
それでは行きますよ、出航！
Alright, here we go, set sail!